<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Markdown | My Site</title>
    <link>https://jiangwenjie0724.github.io/en/tags/markdown/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jiangwenjie0724.github.io/en/tags/markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Markdown</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jiangwenjie0724.github.io/media/icon_hu_645fa481986063ef.png</url>
      <title>Markdown</title>
      <link>https://jiangwenjie0724.github.io/en/tags/markdown/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight Markup Languages</title>
      <link>https://jiangwenjie0724.github.io/en/publication/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiangwenjie0724.github.io/en/publication/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightweight markup languages are convenient tools for structuring text with minimal syntax. They are widely used in blogs, technical documentation, academic publications, and educational materials. Their main advantage lies in their simplicity of writing and the ease of converting content into multiple formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-features&#34;&gt;Key Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimal syntax&lt;/strong&gt; – the markup is easily readable in its raw form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexible export&lt;/strong&gt; – capability to convert text into HTML, PDF, DOCX, and other formats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Versatility&lt;/strong&gt; – applied in academia, programming, and document management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version control compatibility&lt;/strong&gt; – such texts are convenient to store in Git repositories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;examples-of-lightweight-markup-languages&#34;&gt;Examples of Lightweight Markup Languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt; – the most popular language, used on GitHub, in project documentation, and blogs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;reStructuredText (reST)&lt;/strong&gt; – widely adopted in the Python ecosystem, particularly for generating documentation with Sphinx.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AsciiDoc&lt;/strong&gt; – a language with extended features, often used for technical documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Textile&lt;/strong&gt; – one of the earlier systems, used in blogs and CMS platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-in-academia&#34;&gt;Use in Academia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightweight markup languages enable students and researchers to quickly prepare reports, articles, and presentations. Combining Markdown with LaTeX ensures a balance between simplicity and academic rigor. This approach allows for the efficient creation of academic portfolios, lab reports, and publications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightweight markup languages have become an integral part of the modern digital environment. They combine ease of use with wide formatting capabilities, making them effective tools for both professional developers and academic researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Week</title>
      <link>https://jiangwenjie0724.github.io/en/post/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiangwenjie0724.github.io/en/post/05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;weekly-results&#34;&gt;Weekly Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first week of September marked the beginning of a new academic stage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attended introductory classes at the university.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organized materials for the discrete mathematics course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learned the basics of working with Jupyter Notebook for data analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepared a presentation for an academic seminar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compiled a list of long-term semester goals related to programming and research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Week</title>
      <link>https://jiangwenjie0724.github.io/en/post/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiangwenjie0724.github.io/en/post/04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;weekly-results&#34;&gt;Weekly Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth week of August helped to consolidate and expand knowledge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started exploring the Pandas library for data analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Studied the basics of graph theory and implemented several algorithms in Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepared a brief review of a scientific paper on machine learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducted an independent study on the efficiency of sorting algorithms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drew up a study plan for September, including additional reading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Week</title>
      <link>https://jiangwenjie0724.github.io/en/post/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiangwenjie0724.github.io/en/post/03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;weekly-results&#34;&gt;Weekly Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third week of August brought new achievements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Studied the basics of working with the NumPy library for data analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read a chapter from a book on computational complexity theory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continued preparing for the fall semester by organizing lecture notes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delved deeper into version control systems and conflict resolution in Git.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compiled a list of scientific conferences I would like to attend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Week</title>
      <link>https://jiangwenjie0724.github.io/en/post/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiangwenjie0724.github.io/en/post/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;weekly-results&#34;&gt;Weekly Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second week of August was dedicated to developing practical skills:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solved problems on the LeetCode platform, focusing on dynamic programming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learned the basics of working with databases and started studying SQL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepared a reading plan on artificial intelligence literature for the upcoming month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyzed my own trial programs, identified, and corrected algorithmic errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started working on a small study project related to text analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Week</title>
      <link>https://jiangwenjie0724.github.io/en/post/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiangwenjie0724.github.io/en/post/01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;weekly-results&#34;&gt;Weekly Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first week of August turned out to be eventful:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Began systematic revision of the algorithms course, focusing on sorting techniques and search methods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learned the basics of working with LaTeX for preparing academic documents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continued exploring GitHub and created a repository for study projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read several papers on the application of machine learning in natural language processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussed potential topics for future research with a fellow student.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
